Mondays are manic. Wednesdays are wild. And Fridays
are about to get a little freaky.
Freaky Friday is a family, fantasy, comedy film directed by Mark Waters.
Mother and daughter bicker over everything -- what Anna wears, whom
she likes and what she wants to do when she's older.
In turn, Anna detests Tess's fiancé.
When a magical fortune cookie switches their personalities, they each get
a peek at how the other person feels, thinks and lives.
Anna Coleman, played by Lindsay Lohan.
Tess Coleman, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Grandpa, played by Harold Gould.
Jake, played by Chad Michael Murray.
Ryan, played by Mark Harmon.
Mr. Bates, played by Stephen Tobolowsky.
Freaky Friday is a 2003 American fantasy comedy film directed by Mark
Waters and written by Heather Hach and Leslie Dixon.
It is based on the 1972 novel by Mary Rodgers and marks the third film adaptation of the
novel, as well as the fifth installment overall in the Freaky Friday franchise.
The film stars Jamie Lee Curtis and Lindsay Lohan as a mother and daughter who
inadvertently switch bodies through the magic of Chinese fortune cookies.
The supporting cast includes Harold Gould, Chad Michael Murray, and Mark Harmon.
Freaky Friday was released theatrically by Walt
Disney Pictures on August 6, 2003.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $160 million
worldwide against a production budget of $26 million.
The film received largely positive reviews from critics, with particular praise for the performances of Lohan and Curtis, the
latter being nominated for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
A sequel titled Freakier Friday was released in 2025, with
Curtis, Lohan, Murray, and Harmon returning.
The film explores themes of high school, concert, sibling
relationship, single parent, talk show.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.